Register of the Patrick Dowd Papers, 1968-1971
Hoover Institution Archives
Patrick Dowd Papers
1968-1971
73052
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, circulars, minutes of meetings, and printed matter, relating to political activities on college campuses, and to the Young Americans for Freedom.
Dowd, Patrick
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, circulars, minutes of meetings, and printed matter, relating to political activities on college campuses, and to the Young Americans for Freedom.
Biographical/Historical note
California state chairman, Young Americans for Freedom, 1969.
Young Americans for Freedom.; Education.; Student movements--United States.; United States--Politics and government.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Letters sent, 1969-1970
  - Letters sent from Young Americans for Freedom National headquarters, 1969
  - Letters sent while Patrick Dowd was Northern California Chairman of the YAF, 1968-1969
  - Letters received, 1968-1970
  - Letters received protesting removal of Patrick Dowd as YAF State Chairman, 1969
- SUBJECT FILE, 1968-1971
  - Charles Edison Youth Fund
  - Young Americans for Freedom (YAF)
    - Attorney General's report on California State Chapter
      - Advisory Board meetings
      - Memoranda and circulars
      - Problems
      - Ponte controversy
    - Conferences (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous
    - National Board
      - Minutes of meetings, 1970
      - Resolution against anarchy
      - Memoranda, circulars, and printed matter
      - Memoranda, circulars, and printed matter (Box 3)
    - National Convention, Credential committee matters, 1969 -
    - Newsletter, YAF in the News
    - Organizational literature
    - Political action programs
    - Regional conferences